[
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 18,
        "y_pos1": 20,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 4,
        "y_pos1": 19,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 10,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 21,
        "y_pos1": 14,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 16,
        "tile1": 37,
        "x_pos1": 11,
        "y_pos1": 18,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Timrod",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A thin fighter.",
            "job": "I fight with valor!",
            "heal": "Couldn't be better!",
            "keyword1": "VALO",
            "keyword2": "BRAV",
            "answer1": "There is no holier spot of ground than where defeated valor lies.",
            "answer2": "Be brave for there is much to dare!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou brave?",
            "yesanswer": "Fortune helps the brave!",
            "noanswer": "Coward."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 15,
        "tile1": 37,
        "x_pos1": 20,
        "y_pos1": 15,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Slithe",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A valiant warrior.",
            "job": "I fight battles!",
            "heal": "Only minor wounds!",
            "keyword1": "BATT",
            "keyword2": "VALO",
            "answer1": "True valor is seen not in the force of arms, but in the force of will!",
            "answer2": "I display my valor in battle.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou valiant?",
            "yesanswer": "Then never flee unless the need is dire!",
            "noanswer": "Coward."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 14,
        "tile1": 37,
        "x_pos1": 15,
        "y_pos1": 7,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "X",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A strange person",
            "job": "I seek the stone",
            "heal": "O.K.",
            "keyword1": "STON",
            "keyword2": "RED ",
            "answer1": "The red stone.",
            "answer2": "Red is for valor a virtue of the avatar!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou an avatar?",
            "yesanswer": "Wow!",
            "noanswer": "Then thou shalt need the red stone in one altar room to get the third part of a key!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 13,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 11,
        "y_pos1": 23,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Max",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "The housekeeper.",
            "job": "I am the housekeeper.",
            "heal": "Good!",
            "keyword1": "HOUS",
            "keyword2": "ROOM",
            "answer1": "I clean the rooms.",
            "answer2": "That's a strange one at the end. People often disappear.",
            "yesnoquestion": "Is there some problem with thy room?",
            "yesanswer": "I am very sorry I will correct it right away!",
            "noanswer": "Oh, thou had me worried!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 12,
        "tile1": 44,
        "x_pos1": 21,
        "y_pos1": 25,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Luke",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A ranger with a far away look.",
            "job": "I seek the inner light!",
            "heal": "Quite well.",
            "keyword1": "LIGH",
            "keyword2": "YEW ",
            "answer1": "I come from Skara Brae and am on my way to Yew.",
            "answer2": "'tis a city based in the virtue of justice!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou been to Skara Brae?",
            "yesanswer": "A fine city!",
            "noanswer": "'tis a spiritual city!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 11,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 1,
        "y_pos1": 1,
        "move": 128,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Nostro",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A withering soul",
            "job": "I built these passages and they walled me in!",
            "heal": "Very near death!",
            "keyword1": "PASS",
            "keyword2": "RUNE",
            "answer1": "This passage runs around the city!",
            "answer2": "The rune is buried in a tower!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Wilt thou lead me out?",
            "yesanswer": "I am saved!",
            "noanswer": "Thou art a cad! and I will still follow!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 10,
        "tile1": 227,
        "x_pos1": 1,
        "y_pos1": 30,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Senora",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A beautiful mage",
            "job": "I am locked up in this tower.",
            "heal": "Well enough.",
            "keyword1": "TOWE",
            "keyword2": "CRIM",
            "answer1": "I am being punished for my crimes.",
            "answer2": "Does not matter, I can help thee!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou have a ship?",
            "yesanswer": "Then thou dost need a sextant ask the barkeep for he knows more!",
            "noanswer": "Too bad."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 9,
        "tile1": 36,
        "x_pos1": 27,
        "y_pos1": 20,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 6,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Gravnor",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A grave fighter.",
            "job": "I search the dungeons.",
            "heal": "So so.",
            "keyword1": "DUNG",
            "keyword2": "STON",
            "answer1": "I seek the red stone.",
            "answer2": "It is found on an altar!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Dost thou have it?",
            "yesanswer": "No wonder I can't find it!",
            "noanswer": "It lies in the dungeon Destard!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 8,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 27,
        "y_pos1": 12,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Aesop",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A small man.",
            "job": "I search for valor!",
            "heal": "Well enough.",
            "keyword1": "VALO",
            "keyword2": "MANT",
            "answer1": "I find that 'tis easy to be brave from a safe distance!",
            "answer2": "The mantra of valor is 'RA' use it in the shrine on the next isle!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Know what I mean?",
            "yesanswer": "Thats my problem.",
            "noanswer": "Thou art brave!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A stern guard.",
            "job": "We guard the gates and these passages!",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "GATE",
            "keyword2": "PASS",
            "answer1": "The gates of Jhelom.",
            "answer2": "These passages are restricted.",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A stern guard.",
            "job": "We guard the gates and these passages!",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "GATE",
            "keyword2": "PASS",
            "answer1": "The gates of Jhelom.",
            "answer2": "These passages are restricted.",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 81,
        "x_pos1": 3,
        "y_pos1": 17,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A stern guard.",
            "job": "We guard the gates and these passages!",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "GATE",
            "keyword2": "PASS",
            "answer1": "The gates of Jhelom.",
            "answer2": "These passages are restricted.",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 7,
        "tile1": 80,
        "x_pos1": 3,
        "y_pos1": 13,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 0,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 32,
        "talks": {
            "name": "a guard",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A stern guard.",
            "job": "We guard the gates and these passages!",
            "heal": "Well.",
            "keyword1": "GATE",
            "keyword2": "PASS",
            "answer1": "The gates of Jhelom.",
            "answer2": "These passages are restricted.",
            "yesnoquestion": "A",
            "yesanswer": "A",
            "noanswer": "A"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 6,
        "tile1": 36,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 8,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 1,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sir Hrothgar",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A mighty warrior!",
            "job": "I fight for valor!",
            "heal": "Excellent.",
            "keyword1": "VALO",
            "keyword2": "SHRI",
            "answer1": "The valiant soul fears not its own visage!",
            "answer2": "The mantra need be known, ask Aesop!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou the most valiant of souls?",
            "yesanswer": "This is not likely!",
            "noanswer": "Thou should seek the shrine of valor!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 5,
        "tile1": 37,
        "x_pos1": 26,
        "y_pos1": 6,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Sir William",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A noble fighter.",
            "job": "I search for valiant fighters!",
            "heal": "Very well.",
            "keyword1": "EVIL",
            "keyword2": "KILL",
            "answer1": "Kill not non-evil creatures but still always stand thy ground!",
            "answer2": "Let them flee instead. never flee uninjured!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou valiant?",
            "yesanswer": "Strive ye to defeat all evil!",
            "noanswer": "I see."
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 4,
        "tile1": 56,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 8,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Bengrod",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A wounded fighter!",
            "job": "I search the dungeons!",
            "heal": "Poor.",
            "keyword1": "DUNG",
            "keyword2": "ROOM",
            "answer1": "I fell in the dungeon 'Destard'.",
            "answer2": "Therein use the stones found in the connecting dungeons!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Hast thou found its altar room?",
            "yesanswer": "It connects with Covetous, Shame and Hythloth!",
            "noanswer": "Find it!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 3,
        "tile1": 47,
        "x_pos1": 27,
        "y_pos1": 24,
        "move": 1,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Lady Donna",
            "pronoun": "She",
            "look": "A 5 foot pregnant woman",
            "job": "I watch over my sheep.",
            "heal": "Fine, all but the lump in my stomach.",
            "keyword1": "PREG",
            "keyword2": "SHEE",
            "answer1": "It's no fun to be pregnant.",
            "answer2": "I can't stand sheep!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Why, art thou the father?",
            "yesanswer": "Wait till I tell my husband!",
            "noanswer": "Thank god!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 2,
        "tile1": 36,
        "x_pos1": 5,
        "y_pos1": 23,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 3,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Lord Robert",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A mysterious warrior.",
            "job": "I battle for Lord British!",
            "heal": "Outstanding!",
            "keyword1": "WARR",
            "keyword2": "BATT",
            "answer1": "Thou must battle long and hard to be a warrior.",
            "answer2": "Battles are few and too many!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Are you a valiant warrior?",
            "yesanswer": "Thou dost deserve the rune, ask Nostro!",
            "noanswer": "Thou art a wimp!"
        }
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 8,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 9,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 83,
        "x_pos1": 7,
        "y_pos1": 5,
        "move": 1,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 24,
        "y_pos1": 4,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 24,
        "y_pos1": 10,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 25,
        "y_pos1": 18,
        "move": 128,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 0,
        "tile1": 82,
        "x_pos1": 22,
        "y_pos1": 27,
        "move": 0,
        "role": "vendor"
    },
    {
        "tlk_id": 1,
        "tile1": 36,
        "x_pos1": 16,
        "y_pos1": 26,
        "move": 0,
        "flag": 5,
        "humility": 0,
        "turningaway": 0,
        "talks": {
            "name": "Geoffrey",
            "pronoun": "He",
            "look": "A 6 foot 5, great warrior.",
            "job": "I lead into battle!",
            "heal": "I am good and strong!",
            "keyword1": "WARR",
            "keyword2": "BATT",
            "answer1": "A great warrior is a valiant warrior!",
            "answer2": "I desire to fight again in battle!",
            "yesnoquestion": "Art thou valiant!",
            "yesanswer": "Perhaps I could someday join thee!",
            "noanswer": "To flee battle shows cowardice!"
        }
    }
]